teachoo.com 2019-08-21

# teachoo: Privacy Policy

Last Updated: 6-April-2019

* * *

We recognize that your privacy is very important and take it seriously. This Privacy Policy describes teachoo’s policies and procedures on the collection, use, disclosure, and sharing of your information when you use the teachoo Service, via the teachoo website, your mobile phone, or through one of teachoo’s applications for mobile devices (e.g., the teachoo iPhone application and android application).This Privacy Policy applies to activities by **Mishmash Education Services Private Limited** and its affiliates and subsidiaries. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms of Service.

**Information we collect**

We collect information directly from individuals, from third-parties and automatically through the Teachoo Platform.

**_Account and Profile Information_** When you create an account and profile on the Teachoo Platform, we collect your name, contact information (including your telephone number, email), and other information you provide, such as topics that you know about or find interesting. Your name, photo, and any other information that you choose to add to your public-facing profile will be available for viewing to users of the Teachoo Platform. Once you create a profile, other users will be able to see in your profile certain information about your activity on the Teachoo Platform, such as the questions and answers you post, your notes, posts, groups, topics of interest to you, the information you list as credentials, and your edits to Your Content. For more information about your choices for publicly displayed information, see the section below about Your Choices.

**_Your Content_** : We collect and store the information and content that you post to the Teachoo Platform, including your questions, answers, posts, photos, and comments. Your Content, date and time stamps, and all associated comments are publicly viewable on the Quora Platform, along with your name. This also may be indexed by search engines and be republished elsewhere on the Internet in accordance with our _Terms of Service_. For more information about what you can change, see the below section on Your Choices.

**_Communications_**. Your contact information will be used to communicate with you (via e-mail, phone, text message, through the Teachoo Platform or otherwise). When you communicate with us (via email, phone, text message, through the Teachoo Platform or otherwise), we may maintain a record of your communication. By disclosing your contact information to Teachoo, you consent to our use of your contact information to communicate with you.

**_Integrated Service Provider and Linked Networks._** You can elect to sign in or sign up to the Teachoo Platform through a linked network (i.e. Facebook or Google), and you can connect your existing Teachoo account with certain third party networks like Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn (each a “Linked Network”). If you elect to sign up through or connect a Linked Network, we receive certain profile and account information about you from the Linked Network. These Linked Networks may also appear in your profile, so that people can find you on these Linked Networks. The specific information provided to us by Linked Networks is determined by these third parties and may vary by network. In all cases, the permissions page for the Linked Network will describe information being shared. You should consult their respective privacy policies for information about their practices. You may elect to use information from the Linked Network to populate your profile on the Teachoo Platform and help you find and follow your contacts on the Teachoo Platform. For information on your choices, including how to disconnect a Linked Network from your Teachoo profile, see the “Your Choices” section below. You may also elect to connect and make and receive payments to and from use through third party networks (“Integrated Service Provider”); if you do so, you will be allowing us to pass to and receive from the Integrated Service Provider your login information and other user data for payment purposes.

**_Automatically Collected Information About Your Activity_**. We use cookies, log files, pixel tags, local storage objects, and other tracking technologies to automatically collect information about your activities, such as your searches, page views, date and time of your visit, and other information about your use of the Teachoo Platform. We also collect and may store information that your computer or mobile device provides to us in connection with your use of the Teachoo Platform such as your browser type, type of computer or mobile device, browser language, IP address, mobile carrier, unique device identifier, location, and requested and referring URLs. ** __** We also receive information when you view content on or otherwise interact with the Teachoo Platform, even if you have not created an account. .

**_Engagement._** **** We collect browsing information – such as IP address and location, date and time stamp, user agent, Teachoo cookie ID (if applicable), URL, unique advertising or content identifiers (if applicable) and time zone, and other information about user activities on the Teachoo Platform, as well as on third party sites and services that have embedded our Teachoo pixels (“Pixels”), widgets, plug-ins, buttons, or related services. See the section below about Teachoo Ads and Personalization for more detailed information about how our Pixels may be used by publishers or users of our advertising services (“Ad Services”) on the Teachoo Platform to enable personalization, as well as your choices related to advertising and personalization. We may also receive information about you from third parties, such as other users, partners (including ad partners), or our affiliated companies.

**How We Use Your Information**

We do not sell your personal data– such as your name and contact information – to third parties to use for their own marketing purposes.

Teachoo uses the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To provide you the services we offer on the Teachoo Platform, communicate with you about your use of the Teachoo Platform, respond to your inquiries, provide troubleshooting, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you in the Teachoo Platform, to suggest followers and content, offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Teachoo Platform.
  * To display interest-based advertising to you in the Teachoo Platform, to improve our advertising and measurement systems so we can show you relevant ads, and to measure the effectiveness and reach of ads and services. For more information, see the Ad Services section below about Teachoo Ads and Personalization.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.
  * To gather metrics to better understand how users access and use the Teachoo Platform; to evaluate and improve the Teachoo Platform, including the Ad Services and personalization, and to develop new products and services.
  * To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.
  * Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy.

**How We Share Your Information**

We share information as set forth below, and where individuals have otherwise consented:

**_Service Providers._** We may share your information with third party service providers who use this information to perform services for us, such as payment processors, hosting providers, auditors, advisors, consultants, customer service and support providers, as well as those who assist us in providing the Ad Services.

**_Affiliates_** _._ The information collected about you may be accessed by or shared with subsidiaries and affiliates of Teachoo, Inc., whose use and disclosure of your personal information is subject to this Privacy Policy.

**_Business Transfers._** We may disclose or transfer information, including personal information, as part of any merger, sale, and transfer of our assets, acquisition or restructuring of all or part of our business, bankruptcy, or similar event.

**_Legally Required._** We may disclose your information if we are required to do so by law.

**_Protection of Rights._** We may disclose information where we believe it necessary to respond to claims asserted against us or, comply with legal process (e.g., subpoenas or warrants), enforce or administer our agreements and terms, for fraud prevention, risk assessment, investigation, and protect the rights, property or safety of Teachoo, its users, or others.

**_Your Content and Activity._** Your Content, including your name, profile picture, profile information, and certain associated activity information is available to other users of the Teachoo Platform and may be viewed publicly. Public viewing includes availability to non-registered visitors and can occur when users share Your Content across other sites or services. In addition, Your Content may be indexed by search engines. See the section below about Your Choices for information about how you may change how certain information is shared or viewed by others.

**_Metrics._** We may share with users of our advertisers or publishers aggregate statistics, metrics and other reports about the performance of their ads or content in the Teachoo Platform such as the number of unique user views, demographics about the users who saw their ads or content, conversion rates, and date and time information. We do not share IP addresses or personal information. We may also allow our advertisers or publishers to use Pixels on the Teachoo Platform in order to collect information about the performance of their ads or content.

**_Anonymized and Aggregated Data._** We may share aggregated or de-identified information with third parties for research, marketing, analytics and other purposes, provided such information does not identify a particular individual.

**Cookies, Pixels and Tracking**

We and our third party providers use cookies, clear GIFs/pixel tags, JavaScript, local storage, log files, and other mechanisms to automatically collect and record information about your usage and browsing activities on the Teachoo Platform and across third party sites or online services. We may combine this information with other information we collect about users. Below, we provide a brief summary these activities.

  * _Cookies._ These are small files with a unique identifier that are transferred to your browser through our websites. They allow us to remember users who are logged in, to understand how users navigate through and use the Teachoo Platform, and to display personalized content and targeted ads (including on third party sites and applications).
  * _Pixels, web beacons, clear GIFs._ These are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, which we use to track the online movements of users of the Teachoo Platform and the web pages of users of our Ad Services, and to personalize content. We also use these in our emails to let us know when they have been opened or forwarded, so we can gauge the effectiveness of our communications.
  * _Analytics Tools._ We may use internal and third party analytics tools, including [_Google Analytics_](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en). The third party analytics companies we work with may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online products and services. Their collection and use of information is subject to their own privacy policies.

**Do-Not-Track Signals.** Please note we do not change system behavior within the Teachoo Platform in response to browser requests not to be tracked. You may, however, disable certain tracking by third-parties as discussed in the Teachoo Ads and Personalization section below. You may also opt out of tracking by Teachoo Pixels, ad described below in Teachoo Ads and Personalization.

**Teachoo Ads and Personalization**

We may display personalized content (including from third party publishers) and personalized ads (including sponsored content), based on information that we have collected via the Teachoo Platform and through our Pixels, widgets, and buttons embedded on third party sites. We also may report aggregated or de-identified information about the number of users that saw a particular ad or content and related audience engagement information to users of our Ad Services and to publishers of content on the Teachoo Platform.

Users of our Ad Services may also provide us with information as part of their ad campaigns, including customer list information (e.g., email addresses and demographic or interest data or) with us in order to create customized audiences for their ad campaigns; we only use this information to facilitate the particular user’s campaign (including ad metrics and reporting to that user) or for fraud detection and security purposes, and we do not disclose these customer lists to third parties (other than our service providers) unless required by law. We also do not disclose to users of our Ad Services the names or identities of their customers that were successfully reached as part of such campaigns.

We may also work with third parties such as network advertisers to serve ads on the Teachoo Platform and on third-party websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms), such as Google AdSense (more info [here)](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/142293?hl=en) and Facebook Audience Network (more info [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217)). These third parties may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you.

In addition to opting out of tracking across sites by our Pixels (see “Your Choices”) section below), you also may opt out of much interest-based advertising on third party sites and through third party ad networks (including Facebook Audience Network and Google AdSense). See “Your Choices” section below for more information about opting out of third-party ad networks (including Facebook Audience Network and Google AdSense).

**How We Protect Your Information**

The security of your information is important to us. Teachoo has implemented safeguards to protect the information we collect. However, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using the Teachoo Platform on a shared or unsecured device.

**Access and Amend Your Information**

You may update or correct your account information at any time by logging in to your account. You may also make a number of other adjustments to settings or the display of information about you as described in more detail in the following section about Your Choices.

**Your Choices**

You may, of course, decline to submit information through the Teachoo Platform, in which case we may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may also control the types of notifications and communications we send, limit the information shared within the Teachoo Platform about you, and otherwise amend certain privacy settings. Here is some further information about some of your choices:

**_Your Content._** You may edit or delete the answers that you post at any time. Any questions you have posted may remain on the Teachoo Platform and be edited by other users. Any deleted content will be removed from third party sites from which it has been shared via Teachoo’s standard sharing features; however we have no control over deletions or changes to Your Content if it has been shared manually by others. When you make edits to Your Content, other users will be able to see the history of those edits in your profile activity and on content edit logs.

**_Emails, Text Messages and Communications_**. When you join the Teachoo Platform by signing up for an account or creating a profile, as part of the service, you will receive the Teachoo digest containing content that we believe may match your interests. As permitted by law, you are also opting to receive other emails and text messages from us that may be of interest to you as a user of the Teachoo Platform. You can manage your email, text messages and notice preferences in your account profile settings, under your Emails and Notifications settings, but note that you cannot opt out of receiving certain administrative or legal notices from us. If you opt-out of receiving emails and text messages about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you transactional e-mails and text messages about your account or any services you have requested or received from us.

Third parties may comment on your postings within the Teachoo Platform. In your profile, under your Privacy Settings, you can adjust whether to allow people to comment on your answers and posts. You can also adjust permissions about who you allow to send you messages on the Teachoo Platform.

**_Followers._** You can block the ability of another Teachoo user to follow you by selecting the setting for this in the other user’s profile. You can change whether or not you follow other users.

**_Topics_**. You can change topics that you follow or that your profile lists as areas that you know about.

**_Credentials_**. You can change your credentials that are displayed in your profile or in connection with a specific answer.

**_Indexed Search_** _._ In your privacy settings, you can control whether your profile and name is indexed by search engines. Changes to privacy settings may only apply on a going-forward basis; for example, your name (e.g., answers and profile) that has already been indexed by search engines may remain indexed for a period of time even after you have turned off indexing, as implementing this change is outside of our control.

**_Deleted or Deactivated Account_**. If you choose Delete Your Account in your privacy settings, then all of Your Content will be removed from public visibility on the Teachoo Platform, and it may not be restored by us, even if you change your mind. If you choose Deactivate Your Account, then you will no longer receive any communications from us, and users will not be able to interact with you; however Your Content will remain on the Teachoo Platform. Once you deactivate your account, you can reactivate it any time by choosing to log in.

**_Pixels._** This setting is tied to your cookies, and, unless you are logged in to the Teachoo Platform, will only be effective on the browser for which you have performed the opt-out.

**_Third Party Ad Networks_**

**_Linked Networks._** You may connect or disconnect your Linked Networks, such as Facebook, through the Account Settings tab in your profile settings, and you may access, amend and delete much of your profile information through your profile settings. Once you disconnect a Linked Network, we will not receive information from that Linked Network going forward; unless you choose to reconnect it. You may also control whether the Linked Networks is visible in your profile.

**Transferring Your Data**

Teachoo is headquartered in India, and has operations, entities and service providers in India and throughout the world. As such, we and our service providers may transfer your personal information to, or access it in, jurisdictions (including India) that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction. We will take steps to ensure that your personal information receives an adequate level of protection in the jurisdictions in which we process it, including through appropriate written data processing terms and/or data transfer agreements.

**Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 (or under the age of 14 for anyone living in Spain or South Korea or under the age of 18 for anyone living in India) or knowingly allow such persons to register. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the relevant age without parental consent, we take steps to delete that information.

**Links to Other Websites**

The Teachoo Platform may contain links to third party sites or online services. We are not responsible for the practices of such third parties, whose information practices are subject to their own policies and procedures, not to this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions or grievances about our practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [_admin@teachoo.com_](mailto:admin@teachoo.com)

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy that materially change how we treat your personal information, we will endeavor to provide you with reasonable notice of such changes, such as via prominent notice in the Teachoo Platform or to your email address of record, and where required by law, we will obtain your consent or give you the opportunity to opt out of such changes. By continuing to use the Teachoo Platform and Teachoo’s services without consenting to the changes or opting out, it will be deemed that you have consented to such changes by your conduct.

**Country-Specific Terms for India**

India law defines ‘sensitive personal information’ to mean information relating to: (i) passwords; (ii) financial information such as bank account/credit card/debit card details; (iii) physical, physiological and mental health condition; (iv) sexual orientation; (v) medical records and history; (vi) biometric information; (vii) any details relating to the above clauses as required for providing you with access to the Teachoo Platform; and (viii) any of the information received under above clauses for processing, stored or processed under lawful contract or otherwise. Unless otherwise specified in the Privacy Policy, ‘personal information’ will include ‘sensitive personal information’ as well. By using the Teachoo Platform and Teachoo’s services, you will be deemed to have consented to Teachoo’s collection, disclosure and transfer of your personal information. By way of illustration, you will have provided us such consent by your conduct if you choose to share your personal information while using the Teachoo Platform, such as by including sensitive personal information in Your Content or by providing sensitive personal information in your registration information.

If an individual in India deletes or deactivates their account, then their personal information will be deleted as per requirements under applicable law.

While transferring personal information collected from individuals in India, we will ensure that it is transferred to entities that offer at least the same levels of data protection as adhered to by us.
